# **SONGYU WANG**

(812) 201-9470 • wangsongyuf@gmail.com songyu-wang.github.io • linkedin.com/in/wangsongyu

#### SUMMARY

Software test engineer (quality assurance specialist) with five years of experience in test strategy design, test automation, test plan, test execution(manual and automated), and test framework/tool development in the highly regulated industry in a SCRUM/Agile environment. Experienced in complex test management and tractability. Have a deep understanding of functional testing with behavior-driven development and test-driven development. Have strong technical acumen with extensive defect and bug identification, triage, reporting, and verification exposures. Oversaw verification and validation regularly for web applications, API services, etc.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Jun 2020 - Present

### Benchling

San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer, Quality

- Participating in multiple company-wide quality-related projects for a cloud company that develops software platforms powering breakthrough research on biotherapeutics, biofuels, and biomaterials
- Advancing the product(React+Flask+GraphQL+SQLalchemy+PostgreSQL+OpenSearch)
  verification and validation by establishing SOP(standard operating procedure) for test
  case management that meets the regulations, designing/implementing a test traceability
  system with Jira/Xray integration, improving E2E (end-to-end) automated testing
  coverage for various teams/components by at least 30% using Cypress, and
  collaborating with various teams/components to create 300+ new E2E test cases
- Worked on various test infrastructure improvements including but not limited to E2E (end-to-end) test framework development/maintenance/integration using Typescript(Cypress+Playwright) and Python, API/mobile test framework consultation, and CI/CD (continuous integration/continuous delivery+deployment) pipeline development/maintenance/management with AWS, Terraform, Buildkite, Webpack, Datadog, Sumologic, Docker and more
- Onboarded new hires for the QE(Quality Engineering) team
- Participated in an early version of GxP (regulations and guidelines applicable to life sciences organizations) product delivery. Helped create the SOP and some of its technical implementation/automation. In addition, acted as a release engineer for more than half a year. Responsibilities include developing release/upgrade plans, finalizing code for release, generating release patches, and performing testing and production environment deployments

### Jul 2018 - Apr 2020

HeartFlow, Inc

Redwood City, CA

Software Engineer in Test

- Oversaw quality and testing for platforms' and services' components in a SCRUM/Agile environment for a medical technology company that develops software used to create 3D models of coronary arteries to analyze blockages and the impact on blood flow
- Supported development and verification of three web applications, three backend/API services and four workflow/product-related components

- Maintained and refactored existing legacy test frameworks to improve stability and speed, continuously deliver new features for newer frameworks
- Implemented and maintained internal tools to support the development and verification effort
- Designed manual and automated tests using Python and JavaScript to refine and verify product requirements prior to launch/implementation
- Discovered and managed hundreds of internal and external defects and bugs
- Conducted verification/validation activities, including developing and executing test plans, reviewing results and writing reports, and collaborate with cross-functional teams to perform functional, regression, and system-level testing, and ensuring all test-related documentation meets the current corporate and federal regulations
- Prepared Test /Risk Traceability Reports to document test execution outcomes and traced each product requirement and risk contributor/mitigator to the test

# **Additional Experience**

- Teaching Assistant (Mar 2017 May 2018) Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology
- Software Engineer in Test, Intern (May 2017 Aug 2017) HeartFlow, Inc
- Software Intern (Feb 2017 May 2017) Rose-Hulman Ventures

# **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

## **University of Ottawa (2021 - Present)**

Ottawa, ON

Master of Computer Science, Leave of absence due to non-academic life events (Completed 18/30 course units all with A+ grades)

Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology (2014 - 2018)

**Terre Haute, IN** 

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Software Engineering

GPA: 3.73/4.00

Scrum.org | Professional Scrum Product Owner I (2019) & Professional Scrum Master I (2018)

**Triplebyte | Generalist Software Engineering (2019)** 

California State Department of Consumer Affairs | Engineer in Training (2020)